wwu.edu 2018-12-10

# Online Privacy Statement | Western Washington University

  1. **ACCEPTANCE OF TERMS** :  Welcome to this website (“Website”) which is published by WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY.  Use of this Website is voluntary.  By using this Website, you consent to the collection and use of your personally identifiable information (“PII”) and non-personal information as described in this Online Privacy Statement.  This Online Privacy Statement governs only the use and disclosure of information collected through this Website.
  2.  **NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY COLLECTS FROM YOU** :  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY automatically collects information about your Internet connection, including but not limited to:
    * The Internet Protocol (IP) address and name of the Internet domain you used to access the Internet
    * The IP address of the website from which you linked directly to a WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY website
    * The date and time you accessed a WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY website
    * The pages you visited
    * The web browser, operating system and any device you used to access a WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY website
    * Your age and gender
    * Categories you are interested in based on previous searches

This information (“non-personal information”) does not identify you personally. WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY uses this non-personal information to monitor the effectiveness of this Website and to consider potential improvements to this Website.  If you wish to opt-out from this information being collected, you may edit your Ads Settings and opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising, or you can download Google’s [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

  1.  **PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY MIGHT COLLECT FROM YOU** :  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY may request that you voluntarily provide certain personally identifiable information (“PII”) to participate in password-protected areas, download information, join WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY mailing lists, engage in payment transactions, or for other purposes.  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY does not collect any PII about you when you visit this Website unless you give WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY that information.  You may choose not to provide WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY with PII via this Website.  
WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY is a state agency and, as such, is subject to laws governing the Preservation and Destruction of Public Records (RCW 40.14).  As WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY determines is appropriate, WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY will maintain or destroy PII you voluntarily provide.
  2.  **USE OF YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION** : Unless there are restrictions on use of your PII or unless WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY tells you otherwise, WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY (or third parties engaged by WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY) may use your PII to:
    *  Administer your participation in the Website;
    * Communicate information WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY thinks may be of interest to you;
    * Fulfill your request for services or materials;
    * Contact you;
    * Conduct research or surveys;
    * Respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process; and
    * Establish or exercise WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY’s legal rights or defend against legal claims.
  3.  **SHARING YOUR INFORMATION** :  Through display, WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY may disclose your PII to other authorized users of this Website.  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY may use third-party service providers and suppliers to facilitate this Website and the services WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY provides, and they may have access to PII.  Authorized users are WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY employees or third parties who have been granted access and have a need to know the information collected in order to fulfill WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY’s mission.  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY may disclose PII to other affiliated institutions and/or if WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY is required to do so by law.  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY is a state agency and is subject to the Public Records Act (RCW 42.56).  As WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY determines it is appropriate to do so, WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY will disclose PII requested pursuant to this law.
  4.  **USE OF COOKIES, APPLETS** **AND** **WEB BEACONS** : WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY sometimes transfers “cookies,” “applets,” and “web beacons” to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser or email application to collect non-personal information about your visit to this Website. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY uses to identify your computer. Applets are small computer applications that relate information back to WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY. A web beacon (also known as a pixel tag or clear GIF) is a tiny transparent image embedded in a webpage or an email to measure usage and activity. In some cases, a web beacon triggers the placement of a persistent cookie on your device.

  5.   **LINKED SITES** :  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY may provide links on this Website to other sites of interest.  Your use of such linked websites is subject to the privacy statements of those providers of those websites.  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY encourages you to be aware when you leave this Website and to read the privacy statements of each website you visit.
  6.  **SECURITY MEASURES** :  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY works hard to protect the security of the information that you provide to WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY.  While WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY strives to protect your information through measures that protect WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY systems, such security cannot be guaranteed.  Consequently, WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY does not insure or warrant the security of information you transmit, and you transmit information through our Website at your own risk.
  7.  **REVIEWING INFORMATION** :  You may contact us via the Business Services division if you wish to discuss any issues regarding your PII.
  8.  **CHANGES** :  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY may change this Online Privacy Statement from time to time.  If WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY does make a change, WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY will post the revised Online Privacy Statement on this Website.  WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY encourages you to review this Online Privacy Statement periodically.

Questions, comments or complaints about the WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY Online Privacy Statement should be submitted to WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY via the WESTERN WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY Business Services office.
